Andrew **Dufresne**

FullStack Java Developer

1021 E 1st Unt 827 Broomfield, CO 80020

309.807.7099

adufresplatinum@gmail.com http://andrewddufresne.com www.github.com/addufres

About

FullStack Java Engineer with a strong desire to grow and develop new and innovative technologies. Strong organizational, technical and analytical skills. Four years of experience in handling sensitive radio frequency equipment. Extensive work with international logistical operations. Professional, efficient and effective. Created and deployed several fullstack applications to AWS EC2 instances using embedded Apache Tomcat servers. Troubleshoot network issues across multiple projects while retaining reliability online. Strong interest in network security and DevOps culture.

Skills

- Java
- Javascript
- JPA
- HTML/CSS
- JavaFF
- Critical Thinking
- Maven
- **Eclipse**
- Spring MVC
- Spring Framework
- Hibernate
- Gradle
- **JPQL**

- JavaServer Pages (JSP)
- SpringBoot
- **Problem Solving**
- MySQL
- Leadership
- Angular

Experience

Farmers Insurance/ Agency Owner

2015-2016, BLOOMINGTON, IL

Key position responsible for the growth and development of the agency from the ground up, in accordance with Farmers Corporate. Key duties include customer and lead acquisition, accounting and bookkeeping, managing employee hire process, coordinate with district manager to allow for steady growth. At time of sale my agency held a contract value of over \$150.000.

The Dufresne Group / Owner Operator

2013-2016, SAN DIEGO/CHICAGO/DENVER

Analyzed industry trends and compiled market research data to make informed plans for the security needs of clients. Managed buying and selling of goods online via third-party sales venues such as eBay and Amazon. Prospected to obtain new accounts while maintaining relationships with existing accounts. Researched public perception of products and services and use information gathered to guide strategy development.

United States Marine Corps / E-4/Corporal 0621/Radio Operator

2010-2014, CAMP PENDLETON, CA

Supervised all communication functions supporting a company of 200 Marines and Sailors. Instructed all new Marines within company on use and troubleshooting of all communications equipment. Acted as custodian for all cryptography for 2nd Battalion 1st Marines, including equipment safeguard. Accounted for more than \$3 million in regulated and sensitive hardware and conducted weekly inventories with 0% errors. Revised, coordinated and implemented 1st Marine Regiment's formal schooling policies to allow for the professional development of over 1000 Marines and Sailors.

Education

Skill Distillery / FullStack Java Developer

2018, GREENWOOD VILLAGE, CO

16-week/50+ hr week intensive programming bootcamp. Technologies taught/practiced include Java SE/EE, Spring, mySQL, hibernate, gradle, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript (JQuery, Node, Angular) and several more. Learned industry best practices in data-modeling, design patterns, and Agile methodologies. Test Driven Development and pair programming were utilized frequently, as well as Linux and git/github.

Lincoln Tech College / Automotive Engineering

2016-2017, DENVER, CO